I'm Jennifer Staab, AI instructor at Eudacity.
我是 Jennifer Staab 是优达学城的 AI 讲师
I'm speaking with Jesse Swidler.
我身边的是 Jesse Swidler
He is a Senior Software Engineer at Eudacity.
他是优达学城的资深软件工程师
Hi Jennifer, it's nice to be here today.
Hi Jennifer 很高兴接受访谈
Yeah I've been working on Web Applications for
我在过去八九年的时间里
the last eight or nine years and I'm happy to talk to you today.
一直都在搞网络应用开发 很高兴和你交流
So, Jesse, as your job as a Software Developer,
Jesse 作为一名软件开发工程师
how do you find Containers useful?
你认为容器有什么作用？
Yeah. Well, I think the Shipping Container or
嗯我认为
Analogy of Containers is
用集装箱打比方
really the best way to understand how Containers make our life easier.
最好理解容器可以给工作带来的诸多便利
Before there were Shipping Containers,
在有集装箱之前
it was very difficult to move things around the World versus now we can put
在世界各地运输货物很难
everything in a nice little box and because they're all in the same box,
现在我们可以将物品放在一个箱子里
we can attach them to a truck and drive them to a Shipyard
将箱子放到卡车上并开到港口
and put them on a Ship or put them on a big boat.
然后放到船上
We can build big expensive tools,
我们可以建造大型昂贵工具
Cranes to move these boxes around,
例如用起重机移动箱子
pick them up and put them different places.
吊起箱子并放到不同的位置
That's how Containers makes our life better.
这就是容器的便利之处
Everything becomes the same and we can develop tooling around that sameness.
一切都封装在一个箱子里 我们可以用工具操作箱子
So, you're saying that using Containers
你是说软件中的容器
in Software is similar to our Shipping Container Analogy?
与集装箱类似吗？
Yeah, yeah.
是的
It just makes life easier because you can have
容器使工作更便利
these tools that are developed for a specific Container,
因为我们可以使用针对特定容器开发的工具
but it doesn't really matter what's in the Container,
容器里有什么并不重要
like it doesn't matter what Software we're running underneath?
例如无论在容器里运行什么软件都没关系 对吗？
That's right Jennifer.
对的
Or I've gone wrong, I've gone astray?
还是我说错了？
So, Containers is not a full Virtual Machine,
容器并不是完全虚拟机
but for beginners, it's probably useful to think about it
但是对于初学者来说 可以这么理解
that way because you're sharing a Colonel with the underlying OS.
因为它与底层操作系统共享操作工具
So, since it's not a full Virtual machine,
因为不是完全虚拟机
what makes it Containers special or better that they're not?
那么容器有什么特殊之处或优势呢？
What are the advantages of not having them as a full Virtual Machine?
不是完全虚拟机有什么优势？
Well, because they're not a full Virtual Machine,
因为不是虚拟机
it's lighter weight on the OS,
所以对操作系统的负载更小
which means the applications can run with very low overhead.
应用的运行开销很少
So, you don't pay a huge penalty for using the Container.
使用容器的代价很小
So, can you tell us how we use Containers with the WorKspace in the Classroom?
那么我们是如何在教室中使用容器运行 WorKspace 的？
With Workspaces, most of
对于 Workspace 来说
the Student Environments are put inside of one of these Containers.
大部分学员环境都封装在容器之中
Because of that, we can put the Containers in
所以我们可以将容器放在教室中
our Environment where they can be deployed to all of the students at the same time.
并同时向所有学员部署学习环境
We can control authorization to them in the same way.
我们可以用相同的方式控制权限
Just like with the Shipping Containers,
就像集装箱一样
we've built tools around exposing Containers for Students.
我们也创建了向学员提供容器的工具
Without the ability to do that,
不这么做的话
we wouldn't be able to make new Workspaces as easily.
我们就无法轻松地新建 Workspace
So, essentially, Workspace is run in Containers?
所以 Workspace 是在容器中运行的？
Yeah. In and through Containers,
是的整个环境
all up and down the stack, we use Container.
都使用了容器
So, basically, when Students log on,
当学员登录并使用 Workspace 时
they're using Workspaces, they're essentially using Containers?
其实就是在使用容器？
Yeah, yeah.
是的
So, they've already used Containers in there nano degrees already?
所以学员已经在纳米学位课程中使用了容器？
Yeah, I mean very directly inside the Workspaces.
是的 他们直接在 Workspace 中用到了容器
But I mean more generally,
通常
every time you use the Internet,
每次使用互联网
you're probably using Containers on a Server somewhere.
都很可能在使用服务器上的某个容器
Oh wow, that's really interesting.
哇 很有意思
I never thought of it like that.
我从来没这么想过
So, what happens, like if we want to update Software in a Workspace,
如果我们要更新 Workspace 中的软件 该怎么办？
how does that affect things?
有何影响？
Well, that's a good thing about Containers.
使用容器的好处是
Is we generally build them through build scripts and because of that,
我们通常通过脚本构建容器
we can just update the script to use
我们可以直接更新脚本
the new dependency and run it again
并使用新的依赖项 然后重新运行脚本
and then we'll have a new Container with the updated Software.
这样就获得了包含更新软件的新容器
Wow that makes updating Software really easy.
哇 更新软件变得好轻松
Yeah.
是的
So, how have Containers made your job as a Software Developer easier for you?
作为软件开发工程师 容器给你的工作带来了哪些便利性？
Containers has really changed everything about the way
容器完全改变了我的工作方式
I do my job because before I use Containers,
因为之前没用容器的时候
it was difficult to split things up the way you want.
很难按照自己的想法拆分逻辑
Now, with Containers, most Software
现在有了容器
development for Web Applications is not via Microservices.
网络应用的大部分开发工作都不需要使用微服务
We break things down in much smaller more manageable units.
我们将代码划分成小很多的单元 并且更好管理
That make sense. So, it's made your life much easier?
有道理所以容器使你的工作更轻松？
It really has.
是的
Well, thank you today for talking with us today.
感谢你接受访谈
I really appreciate you talking to us about Containers.
很高兴你能跟我们介绍容器知识
I feel like now I have a better understanding of Containers because I
我对容器有更深的理解了
realize how they're connected to the Workspaces that we use at Eudacity.
现在我知道优达学城的 Workspace 就用到了容器
Thanks for talking with me.
谢谢邀请我